Roman Sypchenko

r.sipchenko@gmail.com | +1 403-200-8512 | Calgary, AB, Canada

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sypchenko Website: https://rs-frontend.com

Github: https://github.com/rsypchenko Medium: https://medium.com/@r.sipchenko

SUMMARY

Software (Frontend) Developer with 8+ years of experience crafting web applications leveraging the latest technologies. Knowledge of performance optimization solutions and a strong understanding of web security best practices. Experience mentoring developers through mentorship, coaching, and knowledge sharing.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, Vue.js, Next.js, Node.js, GraphQL, Redux, Redux Toolkit, React Hooks, Apollo Client, HTML, CSS, SASS, SCSS, Tailwind CSS, Material UI, Bootstrap, Styled Components, Cypress, Jest, React Testing Library, Enzyme, Webpack, Git, GitHub, GitLab, Jira, Confluence, Docker, OpenShift, AWS.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

BEST BUY, Canada

Software (Frontend) Developer II

Feb 2023 – present

- Maintained and contributed to large high-load e-commerce project
- Working closely with GitOps, setting up CI/CD for new services with OpenShift and ArgoCD
- Developed and contributed to new company projects, including new customer features
- Increased test coverage for existing components by unit and end-to-end tests utilizing Cypress, Jest, and React Testing Library.

AUTO1 Group SE (Europe's leading platform for buying and selling used cars online), Germany

Frontend Developer

Dec 2021 - Nov 2022

- Built and contributed financing tools for large-scale micro-frontend projects.
- Moved legacy code to new micro-frontend architecture using React.js, TypeScript, GraphQL
- Collaborated with QA team to improve quality of existing components and covered more components by autotests and added more use-cases
- Developed and improved 10+ existing and new reusable components for a custom UI library.

Everest Media (Advertising network), Montenegro

Lead Frontend Developer

Aug 2020 - Dec 2021

- Build and contributed high-load advertising project
- Designed and Implemented an internal framework that increased development speed by 25%
- Mentored a team of 5 front-end developers to improve their technical and soft skills and increased the speed and code quality of project development
- Involved in hiring pipeline: CV screening, interviewing candidates, evaluating tech assessments.

Finline (Fintech startup), Ukraine

Senior Frontend Developer

Oct 2016 – Aug 2020

- o Build and designed education platforms (Financing, Crypto)
- o Developed UI for a crypto platform that allowed analysis using charts and tools for buying and selling stock and crypto assets.

- o Designed and developed an education platform for financing and crypto traders.
- o Worked on building responsive single-page web applications using cutting-edge technologies and complex business logic.

• Full Stack Developer

Aug 2014 – Oct 2016

- o Developed and maintained back office and UI tools for our clients that increased the quality of service and product support.
- o Designed and developed web chat for the support team that allows our clients quickly solve issues and get better service.

EDUCATION

Alfred Nobel University, Ukraine Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

Sep 2008 – Jun 2011